# CHAN KAI CHUNG, AARON ASA

Flat F, 10/F, Block 9, Park Central, Tseung Kwan O, Hong Kong \* (852) 9680-4043 \* dbsackc@gmail.com

Passionate mathematics graduate with 10+ years' experience in applied mathematics, in the field of actuarial science. Strong programming background in secondary school and undergraduate education focusing on MatLab and R. Heavily trained in quantitative skills and logical reasonings. Motivated multi-tasker who has proven project management and excellent communication skills

### **EDUCATION**

# The Chinese University of Hong Kong

2006 - 2010

Bachelor of Science with Honours, Second Upper-Class Division

- Major in Mathematics (Computational and Applied Mathematics Stream)
- Minor in Statistics

Cumulative GPA: 3.369/4.000, Major GPA: 3.443/4.000

- Related Mathematics courses included advanced calculus (B+ up), linear algebra (B+ up), Optimization Theory (A-)
- Related Computer Science courses included Mathematics Laboratory (A- up) and Introduction to Programming Language for Statistics (A-)
- Completed courses relating to Statistics, Economics, Finance, and other areas with highly satisfactory results
- Attended the University of Sheffield, UK as exchange student in 2008-2009 to gain overseas exposure

#### **ACADEMIC HONOURS AND AWARDS**

Mr. Yan-Ding Poon Mathematics Scholarship (by Department of Mathematics)

2008

Dean's List in Faculty of Science

2007

# **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

Associate of the Society of Actuaries

## **CAREER EXPERIENCE**

# **Actuarial Manager**

Jun 2020 – Current

Prudential (Hong Kong) Limited

- Actuarial manager focusing on life insurance product developments and pricing
- Main duties include insurance market research, actuarial modelling, product feature design and pricing, system development & UAT
- Manage a team of three, allocate tasks and review work to ensure quality and timely response of deliverables
- Trained to deal with large amount of data for financial results-oriented projects

# Actuarial Analyst to Manager

Jan 2011 - Mar 2019

Deloitte Advisory (Hong Kong) Limited

- 2 years of manager plus 6 years of working level experience, involving in various advisory projects
- Focusing in the South East Asia market, projects involved include Insurance Product Pricing, Actuarial Modelling and Actuarial Reporting
- Frequently involved in ad-hoc tasks that requires automation, forecast modelling and solving dynamic financial optimization problems

## OTHER CAPABILITIES AND SKILLS

Languages: Native in Cantonese, Fluent in English and Mandarin Computer Skills: Professional in Microsoft Office, R, MatLab and VBA